yamahamotorsports.com 2014-06-25

# Privacy Policy page of Yamaha Motor Corporation U.S.A.

****

Thank you for visiting the Privacy Policy page of Yamaha Motor Corporation U.S.A.'s ("Yamaha") website. Yamaha values your right of privacy, and wants you to feel comfortable using its website at [http://www.yamaha-motor.com](http://www.yamaha-motor.com/) (the "Yamaha Website" or "Website"). This page describes our privacy policy for the Website, and enables you to opt out of certain uses and disclosures of your personally identifiable information. 

**1\. Your Acceptance**  
By using and/or visiting the Yamaha Website, you signify your assent to both the content of this Privacy Policy and the general Terms and Conditions for using the Website, which are published at <http://www.yamaha-motor.com/corporate/gen_terms.aspx>, and which are incorporated herein by reference. If you do not agree to any of these terms, you should not use the Website. Should Yamaha make any substantial change to this Privacy Policy, we will publish an amendment, or we may email you if you have not opted out of email notifications.

**2\. Yamaha Website**  
This Privacy Policy applies solely to the Yamaha Website, which may contain links to third party websites that are not owned or controlled by Yamaha. For instance, if you apply for Yamaha Factory Financing or establish a Yamaha Card Account, you may access the independent website of Capital One, N.A. or another third party. Yamaha has no control over, and assumes no responsibility for, the content, privacy policies, or practices of any third party website, which may collect both passive and personally identifiable information. In addition, Yamaha will not and cannot censor or edit the content of any third party site. By using the Website, your expressly relieve Yamaha from any and all liability arising from your use of any third party website. Accordingly, we encourage you to be aware when you leave the Yamaha Website, and to read the terms and conditions and privacy policy of each other website that you visit.

**3\. What Type of Information Do We Collect and Use?**  
When you visit the Yamaha Website, we may collect passive information about your visit. Passive information is any form of aggregate data, navigational data, tracking data, click-stream data, or historical data, which does not on its own personally identify you. Passive Information includes information collected through cookies and web beacons. When you register a product, apply for extended service through our YES program, send us an email, subscribe to one of our newsletters, or submit other data through the Yamaha Website, we may also obtain and collect personally identifiable information. Personally identifiable information is information collected online that personally identifies you, such as by name, email address, or mailing address. Yamaha provides you with the ability to "opt-out" of certain uses of such personally identifiable information. 

**4\. Maintenance & Opt-Out of Information**  
If you wish to opt-out of our use and disclosure of your personally identifiable information, other than as expressly permitted in this Privacy Policy, you will have the option to do so when you first submit your personally identifiable information via the Yamaha Website. Simply state your desire to opt-out where indicated. If you wish to amend or delete any personally identifiable information that you have previously provided without opt-out, please send us a message at [privacy@yamaha-motor.com](mailto:privacy@yamaha-motor.com). We will endeavor to provide a simple way to review, correct, update or remove personally identifiable information you have given us. If you wish to stop receiving a Yamaha newsletter or other circulation, please follow the "unsubscribe" instructions contained in each newsletter.

**5\. How Do We Use Personally Identifiable Information?**  
If you have opted out of our general use of personally identifiable information, Yamaha will not use or disclose such information except as follows:

\- to communicate directly with you in connection with your specific requests;  
\- to validate credit card numbers;  
\- to permit our website designers to develop features and services that meet your needs;  
\- to tailor your experience on our Website, showing you individually tailored content;  
\- to comply with a lawful subpoena or court order;  
\- to remedy any violation or breach of an agreement between you and Yamaha; and  
\- to prevent harm to the property or rights of Yamaha or its customers.

If you have not "opted-out" of our use and disclosure of your personally identifiable information, Yamaha may also use such information for its own marketing and survey purposes, and Yamaha may appoint third party agents in connection with such marketing and survey efforts, subject to a confidentiality agreement concerning the information. Yamaha will not, however, disclose any personally identifiable information for use in connection with a third party's marketing efforts.

**6\. Aggregate Information**  
Yamaha may share aggregate statistical information with business partners, sponsors or other third parties, but none of them receive personally identifiable information. For example, we may tell an advertiser that X number of visitors visited a certain area on a website, or that Y number of men and Z number of women applied for extended service, but we would not disclose anything that uniquely identifies those individuals.

**7\. Unsolicited Emails Received by You**  
Yamaha does not send unsolicited bulk emails to anyone who has requested that we do not contact them. We send newsletters only to those who have taken affirmative steps to subscribe. If you have inadvertently received one of our newsletters, or if you simply wish to stop receiving them, please follow the "Unsubscribe" instructions contained in each newsletter or send a request to be unsubscribed to [privacy@yamaha-motor.com](mailto:privacy@yamaha-motor.com).

**8\. Cookies**  
Your browser software includes a feature called "cookies." We may use "cookies" to enhance your experience with our site. If enabled, cookies may store small amounts of data on your computer about your visit to the Yamaha Website, including your page preferences. Cookies tell us nothing about you personally, unless you specifically give us additional information. Yamaha does not merge or associate our cookie information with any personally identifiable information obtained by us or from third parties. Cookies simply assist us in tracking which of our features you like best and what content you may have viewed during past visits. When you re-visit the Yamaha Website, cookies can enable us to customize our content according to your preferences. We may use cookies to: (i) keep count of your return visits to the Website; (ii) accumulate anonymous, aggregate, statistical information on website usage; (iii) deliver content specific to your interests or past viewing history; and (iv) save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit our sites. You can also disable cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you can accept or reject all cookies, or request a notification when a cookie is set. 

**9\. P3P (Platform for Privacy Preference) Conformance**  
Our cookies conform to the emerging P3P privacy standard, developed by the World Wide Web Consortium. P3P provides a simple, automated way for users to control the use of personal information. Browsers like Microsoft Internet Explorer 6.0 conform to the P3P standard. At its most basic level, P3P is a standardized set of multiple-choice questions, covering all the major aspects of a website's privacy policy. Taken together, they present a clear snapshot of how a site handles personal information. P3P-enabled browsers can "read" this snapshot automatically and compare it to the consumer's own set of privacy preferences. P3P places privacy policies where users can find them, in a form users can understand, and, most importantly, enables users to act on what they see. 

**10\. IP Addresses**  
An Internet Protocol ("IP") address is a number assigned to your computer whenever you access the Internet. An Internet Service Provider ("ISP") typically assigns a random dynamic IP address at the time of your dial-up. For local area network ("LAN"), DSL, or cable modem users, a static IP address may be permanently assigned to a particular computer. Yamaha may record the IP addresses of visitors to its Website. While an IP address may reveal your ISP or geographic area, we cannot determine your identity solely based upon your IP address. Other websites you visit have IP addresses, and we may collect the IP addresses of those websites and their pages, but these IP addresses are never associated with Internet users.

**11\. Web Beacons**  
The Website may contain web beacons, which are electronic images (sometimes called "single-pixel gifs") that allow us to count page views, or to access cookies. We may also include web beacons in HTML-formatted newsletters containing graphics that we may send to opt-in subscribers, to count the number of newsletters that have been opened and read. Our web beacons do not collect, gather, monitor, or share any personal information about our website visitors. They are used only to compile our anonymous, aggregate statistics about website usage.

**12\. Computer Profiles**  
Yamaha may also collect and accumulate other anonymous data that helps us understand and analyze the Internet experience of our visitors. For example, we may accumulate visitor data relating to referring domain names, the type of browsers used, operating system software, screen resolutions, color capabilities, browser plug-ins, language settings, cookie preferences, search engine keywords and JavaScript enablement. None of this information is personally identifiable and we only share this information in the aggregate, reflecting overall website or Internet usage trends, as outlined in this Privacy Policy.

**13\. Chat Rooms and Forums**  
The Yamaha Website may in the future include chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups. If so, Yamaha as a passive conduit will not be liable for any of the transmitted information. Any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information. You should exercise caution before disclosing your personal information via these public venues, which you do at your own risk. If you do so, you may receive unsolicited emails or "spam." Yamaha cannot safeguard the privacy of personally identifiable information that is disclosed and can be viewed or accessed online in this manner.

**14\. Security**  
Some pages of the Yamaha Website use security measures to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of information that is transmitted through the Website. These pages use Secure Socket Layer ("SSL") connections with 128-bit encryption for certain transactions and confidential data. When you use a secure browser, all information you submit comes to us over the Internet in an encrypted form, with a digital certificate issued by a third-party certification authority such as VeriSign®. To view this certificate, click on the image of the closed lock or the solid key on the bottom bar of your browser window. We also maintain our servers in locked facilities with secure access. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personally identifiable information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems. You can report network abuse and any risk of security violations to us by emailing privacy@yamaha-motor.com.

**15\. Children's Online Privacy Protection**  
The Yamaha Website complies with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA). COPPA and its accompanying FTC regulation protects the privacy of children using the Internet. Yamaha does not knowingly collect contact or personally identifiable information from children under 13. The Yamaha Website is not intended to solicit information of any kind from children under 13, and is designed to block our knowing acceptance of any such information, wherever age related information is requested. It is possible that by fraud or deception we may receive information pertaining to children under 13. If we are notified of this, as soon as we verify the information, we will immediately obtain parental consent or otherwise delete the information from our servers. If you want to notify us of our receipt of information by children under 13, please do so by emailing us at privacy@yamaha-motor.com.

**16\. Contact Information**  
If you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [privacy@yamaha-motor.com](mailto:privacy@yamaha-motor.com), or at the following address:  
Yamaha Motor Corporation, U.S.A.  
Attn: Online Privacy Manager  
6555 Katella Avenue  
Cypress, California 90630-5101
